In this module, you will learn to read code and execute it by hand.
在本模块中，您将学习阅读代码并手动执行代码。当@@
Why would you want to do this when you could take a quick syntax lesson and
你可以上一堂简短的语法课然后
start typing?
开始打字时，你为什么要这样做？
Think for a moment about when you were first learning about written language.
想一想你第一次学习书面语言是什么时候。
Did you learn to write before you could read?
你在读书之前学会写作了吗？
Probably not, recognizing a word or sentence and
可能不是，识别单词或句子并
attaching meaning is easier than formulating your own.
附上含义比表达自己的含义要容易得多。
You've probably misspelled a word or
你可能拼错了一个单词或者
made a grammatical error expressing an idea that you could read just fine.
犯了一个语法错误，表达了一个你可以很好地阅读的想法。
Programming is much like this, you need to read for understanding and understand
编程就是这样，你需要
exactly how code is executed before you can write good code of your own.
先阅读才能理解并准确理解代码是如何执行的，然后才能自己写出好的代码。
It's also easier, reading well will help you make fewer mistakes as you go, but
它也更容易，读得好可以帮助你减少边走边犯的错误，
also help you troubleshoot when your code does something you did not expect.
还可以帮助你在代码做一些你没想到的事情时进行故障排除。
My background is in mechanical engineering, and
我的背景是机械工程，在
in my undergraduate program, we used MATLAB for computational tasks.
我的本科课程中，我们使用 MATLAB 来完成计算任务。
Despite excellent instruction and
尽管有很好的指导和
thoughtful exercises, many students, myself included,
周到的练习，但许多学生，包括我自己，还是
would spend hours debugging code, mostly by guessing and checking.
会花几个小时调试代码，主要是通过猜测和检查。
Never once did I draw a picture of what I thought was happening, or
我从来没有画过我以为正在发生的事情，
execute even a line of code by hand.
甚至从未用手执行过一行代码。
And I probably couldn't have,
而且我可能做不到，
because there were a few things I didn't understand fully.
因为有几件事我没有完全理解。
While teaching, I've seen students make similar mistakes.
在教学中，我看到学生会犯类似的错误。
Finding the cause of an error message is a treasure hunt, one that might take much
找出错误消息的原因是一次寻宝，这可能
longer than someone spent writing the code in the first place.
比最初花在编写代码上的时间长得多。
Often, we know what we want a section of code to be doing, maybe even what we think
通常，我们知道我们想要一段代码做什么，甚至可能知道
it's doing, but unless you can be sure, you cannot be confident in your result.
它在做什么，但是除非你能确定，否则你无法对自己的结果充满信心。
And you'll likely spend more time debugging than you want to.
而且你花在调试上的时间可能会比你想要的要多。
Here's an algorithm for a function we'll talk about later in the course.
以下是我们将在本课程后面讨论的函数的算法。
You can see here that each step of the algorithm
你可以在这里看到，算法的每个步骤
changes something about the state of the program.
都会改变程序的状态。
Here are the same steps implemented in code.
以下是在代码中实现的相同步骤。
Do not worry if you do not know how to read this yet.
如果您还不知道如何阅读这篇文章，请不要担心。
The point is that the code needs to change the program
关键是代码需要以与
in the exact same way as your algorithm.
算法完全相同的方式更改程序。
If the code is doing something different,
如果代码做了不同的事情，
we need to change it to match the algorithm.
我们需要对其进行更改以匹配算法。
This is why learning to read code is so important for writing it.
这就是为什么学习阅读代码对编写代码如此重要的原因。
In this module, you'll learn to understand what statements do.
在本模块中，您将学会理解语句的作用。
Both the syntax, or grammar of a language, and
语言的语法或语法，以及语
the semantics, or meaning a statement has.
句的语义或含义。
You'll also learn how to keep track of the state of a program, where you are, and
你还将学习如何跟踪程序的状态、你在哪里，以及
what functions can see which variables.
哪些函数可以看到哪些变量。
To do this, you will learn how to draw pictures of exactly what is happening
为此，您将学习如何
according to a set of rules.
根据一组规则准确地描绘正在发生的事情。
Once you can do these things, writing code will come easier.
一旦你能做到这些事情，编写代码就会变得更加容易。
And when you do have a situation when your code does not do what you expect,
而且，当你的代码确实没有达到预期的效果时，
you'll have a set of tools you can use to investigate your program to see what it is
你可以使用一组工具来调查你的程序，看看它在
doing.
做什么。